A Guide to the Susana Torre Architectural Papers, 1967-2003
Special Collections, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
- Series I: Project Records 1971-1989
  - Montauk Public Library, Montauk, NY, 1985-1989
    - De Pouli's Scheme (Box-folder 7:21)
    - Environmental Impact Statement (Box-folder 7:22)
    - Estimates (Box-folder 7:23)
    - Estimate Revisions (Box-folder 7:24)
    - Final State Submissions (Box-folder 7:25)
    - Furniture/Equipment (Box-folder 7:26)
    - Library Committee (Box-folder 7:27)
    - Library Research (Box-folder 7:28-29)
    - Lighting Cuts/Elevator (Box-folder 7:30)
    - Mechanical (Box-folder 7:31)
    - Minutes (Box-folder 7:32)
    - New York State, Department of Environmental Conservation - The State Environmental Quality Review Act (SEQR) Handbook (Box-folder 7:33)
    - Phone Memos (Box-folder 7:34)
    - Preliminary State Submissions (Box-folder 7:35)
    - Press (Box-folder 8:1)
    - Products (Box-folder 8:2)
    - Program (Box-folder 8:3)
    - Property (Box-folder 8:4)
    - Quality Control (Box-folder 8:5)
    - Revised Estimate Worksheets (Box-folder 8:6)
    - Revised Estimate Worksheets (Box-folder 8:7)
    - Sample Submissions (Box-folder 8:8)
    - Schedule of Values (Box-folder 8:9)
    - Ship Documents (Box-folder 8:10)
    - Site (Box-folder 8:11)
    - Site Requirements (Box-folder 8:12)
    - Space Planning (Box-folder 8:13)
    - Specifications (Box-folder 8:14)
    - Sprinklers (Box-folder 8:15)
    - Structures (Box-folder 8:16)
    - Suppliers (Box-folder 8:17)
    - Survey-Soil (Box-folder 8:18)
    - Town/State Regulations (Box-folder 8:19)
    - Transmittal-Incoming (Box-folder 8:20)
    - Transmittal-Outgoing (Box-folder 8:21)
    - Utilities (Box-folder 8:22)
    - WASA (Box-folder 8:23)
    - Windows (Box-folder 8:24)
    - Architectural Drawings (Oversize 12-13)
  - CW Post Campus Dormitories, Long Island University, NY, 1985
    - Drawings (Box-folder 8:25)
    - Research (Box-folder 8:26-27)
  - Residence for Carpenter and Simpkins, NY, 1985-1986
    - Contract (Box-folder 8:28)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 8:29)
    - Products (Box-folder 8:30)
    - Site details (Box-folder 8:31)
    - Schematics (Box-folder 8:32)
  - Fire Station, Jersey City, NJ, 1985-1986
    - Products (Box-folder 8:33)
    - Documents (Box-folder 8:34)
    - Architectural Drawings (Oversize 14)
  - Prof. Arthur Danto's Office, Columbia University, New York, NY, 1985 (Box-folder 8:35)
  - Hostos Community College, NY, 1985
    - Presentation documents (Box-folder 9:1)
    - Proposal for design of new facilities (Box-folder 9:2)
  - WASA Office Renovation, 1985 (Box-folder 9:3)
  - Hand of Mann Condominiums, NJ, 1985-1986
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:4)
    - Drawings (Box-folder 9:5)
  - University Press Bookstore, New School, NY, 1985-1986
    - Preliminary documentation (Box-folder 9:6)
    - Construction drawings and documents (Box-folder 9:7)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:8)
    - Cost estimates (Box-folder 9:9)
    - Field reports (Box-folder 9:10)
    - Products (Box-folder 9:11)
    - Schematic designs (Box-folder 9:12)
    - Architectural Drawings (Oversize 15)
  - Law Library Renovation, Columbia University, New York, NY, 1985-1987
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:13)
    - Notes and sketches (Box-folder 9:14)
  - Headquarters Addition for Iron Workers, NY, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 9:15)
  - Law Office Renovation, Harry Torcyzner, NY, 1987
    - Project Documents (Box-folder 9:16)
    - Architectural Drawings (Oversize 16)
  - Addition to Residence for Miller, 1987-1988
    - Project Documents (Box-folder 9:17)
    - Architectural Drawings (Oversize 17)
  - Furniture for Clark House, NY, 1988 (Box-folder 9:18)
  - D'Agostino Development, NY, 1988 (Box-folder 9:19)
  - Hampton Medical Center, NY, 1988 (Box-folder 9:20)
  - Shepler Apartment Renovation, 1988 (Box-folder 9:21)
  - Olympic Boulevard Competition, 1988 (Box-folder 9:22)
  - Middle School Competition, OH, 1988
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:23)
    - Catalogs (Box-folder 9:24)
  - Renovation, Gurley Apartment, 1988 (Box-folder 9:25)
  - Tapper Wood Deck, NY, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 9:26)
  - Jewett Arts Center, Wellesley College, MA, 1988-1989
    - Research file (Box-folder 9:27)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:28)
  - Pratt Institute Renovation Competition, 1988
    - Public lecture (Box-folder 9:29)
    - Drawings and documents (Box-folder 9:30)
  - U.S. Pavilion Expo, Seville, Spain, 1988
    - Forms and submissions (Box-folder 9:31)
    - Correspondence (Box-folder 9:32)
  - Walter Reed Army Medical Center, MD, 1989 (Box-folder 9:33)
  - Library Addition, Bard College, 1989
    - Forms and submissions (Box-folder 9:34)
    - Research (Box-folder 9:35)
    - Notes (Box-folder 9:36)
  - Wencelblat Apartments, Argentina, 1989 (Box-folder 9:37)
  - Photographs of unidentified project sites and of a model, n.d. (Oversize 18)
- Series II: Professional Papers, 1830-1994
  - Subseries A: Professional and Cultural Organizations 1974-1994
    - Architectural League of New York (ALNY), 1974-1994
      - General file (Box-folder 10:1)
      - Arts and architecture projects (Box-folder 10:2)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 10:3)
      - School project (Box-folder 10:4)
    - Commons, 1976
      - Documents (Box-folder 10:5)
      - Prospectus (Box-folder 10:6-7)
    - Heresies, 1976-1989
      - General files (Box-folder 10:8-9)
      - Notes (Box-folder 10:10)
      - Women in Architecture, 1976-80 (Box-folder 10:11-12)
    - Chrysalis, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10:13)
    - Networks: Women in Architecture, 1977-1979
      - Documents (Box-folder 10:14)
      - Contacts (Box-folder 10:15)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 10:16)
    - Regional Health Planning Committee, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10:17)
    - Terrible 12, 1979 (Box-folder 10:18)
    - Judy Chicago's Dinner Party, 1979 (Box-folder 10:19)
    - EFL: Architectural Fellowships, 1979 (Box-folder 10:20)
    - Architects for Social Responsibility (ASR), 1982-1984 (Box-folder 10:21)
    - JAE: Journal of Architectural Education, 1982-1985
      - Documents (Box-folder 10:22)
      - Correspondence (Box-folder 10:23)
    - Circulo De Cultura Cubana, Inc., 1983 (Box-folder 10:24)
    - Alliance of Women in Architecture, 1985 (Box-folder 10:25)
    - International Archive of Women in Architecture (IAWA), 1987-1990 (Box-folder 10:26)
    - City College of New York, School of Architecture, 1989 (Box-folder 10:27)
    - Alliance of the Building Community, 1989-90 (Box-folder 10:28)
    - ASCA Task Force on the Status of Women in Architecture Schools, 1989-91 (Box-folder 10:29)
    - Architects/Designers/Planners for Social Responsibility (ADPSR), New York, 1990-1991
      - Clippings (Box-folder 10:30)
      - Documents (Box-folder 10:31)
      - Forum correspondence (Box-folder 10:32)
      - Forum documents (Box-folder 10:33)
      - Forum papers (Box-folder 10:34)
      - Notes and correspondence (Box-folder 10:35)
    - Ferri-Torre Non-profit Corporation, n.d. (Box-folder 10:36)
  - Subseries B: Publications, 1967-1992
    - Art Criticism in Argentina 1967-1969 (Box-folder 11:1)
    - Publications, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 11:2-3)
    - Publications, 1973 (Box-folder 11:4)
    - Publications, Cuban Article, 1974 (Box-folder 11:5-6)
    - Publications, 1975 (Box-folder 11:7)
    - Publications, Women in Architecture, 1977 (Box-folder 11:8)
    - Publications, 1977 (Box-folder 11:9-10)
    - "A Selection of Project Reviews and Writings" 1977-1988 (Box-folder 11:11)
    - Misc. Selection of Project Reviews and Writings 1989-1996 (Box-folder 11:12)
    - Publications, 1978 (Box-folder 11:13)
    - Publications, 1979 (Box-folder 11:14-15)
    - Publications, 1980 (Box-folder 11:16-17)
    - Publications, 1981 (Box-folder 11:18-21)
    - Publications, 1982 (Box-folder 11:22)
    - Publications 1983 (Box-folder 11:23)
    - Ideas for Publications n.d. (Box-folder 11:24)
    - Publications, "W our name is Women," 1983 (Box-folder 11:25)
    - Publications, 1985 (Box-folder 11:26-28)
    - Publications, 1986 (Box-folder 11:29)
    - Publications, 1987 (Box-folder 11:30)
    - Publications, Room in the City, 1987 (Box-folder 11:31)
    - Publications, 1988 (Box-folder 12:1)
    - Publications, 1989 (Box-folder 12:2)
    - Borderlands Sourcebook, 1988 (Box-folder 12:3)
    - Lecture at Virginia Tech (VPI), Videotape, October 23, 1989 (Box-folder 12:4)
    - Publications, Women in Architecture 1990 (Box-folder 12:5)
    - Publications, 1990-1992 (Box-folder 12:6-7)
    - Notes for New Journal: "PRO-JECT" n.d. (Box-folder 12:8)
    - Book chapter, Mary Otis Stevens, 2003 (Box-folder 12:9)
  - Subseries C: Research Files about Women in Architecture, 1830-2001
    - Materials for Exhibit and Book, Women in American Architecture, 1898-1978
      - Research Materials (Box-folder 13:1-7)
      - Correspondence for Traveling Exhibition and Book, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 13:8-9)
      - Photographs and Negatives Gathered for Book, 1977 (Box-folder 13:10-11)
      - Blueprints of exhibit panels (Oversize 19)
    - Materials about Specific Women, 1830; 1968-2000
      - Adams, Ruth, 1977 (Box-folder 13:12)
      - Fisher, Karen, 1975 (Box-folder 13:13)
      - Gray, Ellen and Badovici. J, 1968, n.d. (Box-folder 13:14)
      - Hayden, Dolores, Essays, 1975-82 (Box-folder 13:15-16)
      - Hommann, Mary, 1969 (Box-folder 13:17)
      - Lobell, Mimi, 1975-83 (Box-folder 13:18)
      - Mahoney Griffin, Marion, Report on Her Life and Work by Dr. Anna Rubbo, 1993 (Box-folder 13:19)
      - Pignatelli, Paola, 1993 (Box-folder 13:20)
      - Pontalba, (The Baroness), 1977-80 (Box-folder 13:21)
      - Prisbrey, ("Grandma"), n.d. (Box-folder 13:22)
      - Spiegel, Susan, n.d. (Box-folder 13:23-24)
      - Stevens, Mary Otis, 2000 (Box-folder 13:25)
      - Tacha, Athena, one sketch, 1975 (Box-folder 13:26)
      - Taylenius, (Mrs.), Original Ink and Watercolor Drawing of Rome, 1830 (Oversize 20)
      - Tyng, Anne Grisworld, 1975 (Box-folder 13:27-28)
      - Vinciarelli, Lauretta, 1973-78 (Box-folder 14:1)
      - Wekerle, Gerda, 1976-79 (Box-folder 14:2)
      - Winchester, Sarah (Mystery House), 1974 (Box-folder 14:3)
      - Wright, Gwendolyn, 1976 (Box-folder 14:4)
      - Unidentified copy photograph of portratit of a woman and girl (Oversize 20)
    - General Materials about Women in Architecture, 1950-1995
      - Women in Architectural Reviews in Magazine of Art, Architecture Plus, and Architectural Design, 1950, 1973, 1975 (Box-folder 14:5)
      - Booklet and Brochure, Women's Buildings, 1973 (Box-folder 14:6)
      - Article, "Factors in the Career Choices of Women in Environmental Design," by Rosaria F. Hogden, University of Oregon, 1977 (Box-folder 14:7)
      - Report, Status of Women in the Architectural Profession, American Institute of Architects (AIA), 1975 (Box-folder 14:8)
      - Essay, Art Education and Art Making From a Feminist Perspective by Maria Karras, 1976 (Box-folder 14:9)
      - Association of Women Architects (AWA), Newsletter and Directory, 1979 (Box-folder 14:10)
      - Recent Documents about Women in Architecture (not in original research files), 1988-95 (Box-folder 14:11)
      - Paper about First Black Women Architects, n.d. (Box-folder 14:12)
      - Women's Cultural Building in Toronto, Judging and Panel Discussion, n.d. (Box-folder 14:13)
- Series III: Faculty Papers 1971-1991
  - Teaching contracts, correspondence, drawings, 1972-1988 (Box-folder 15:1)
  - SUNY-Old Westbury
    - Student work, 1971-1975 (Box-folder 15:2-3)
    - College catalogs, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15:4)
    - College catalogs, clippings, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 15:5)
    - Course descriptions and proposals, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 15:6)
    - Political appropriation of space, Fall 1973 (Box-folder 15:7)
    - Consultantship, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15:8)
  - College of Old Westbury, Papers, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15:9)
  - Pratt Institute
    - Concepts of Design, Student evaluations, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 15:10)
    - Concepts of Design, Course outline, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 15:11)
    - Lectures and notes, n.d. (Box-folder 15:12)
  - New Jersey School of Architecture
    - Correspondence and course description, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15:13)
    - Notes, 1977 (Box-folder 15:14)
    - Correspondence and clippings, n.d. (Box-folder 15:15)
    - Magazine clippings and notes, n.d. (Box-folder 15:16)
  - Nova Scotia Technical College, Halifax, Correspondence, 1977 (Box-folder 15:17)
  - University of California, Cooper Union, NY, Teaching documents, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 15:18)
  - Syracuse University
    - Studio documents, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 15:19)
    - Seminar, Architectural Typologies, 1979 (Box-folder 15:20)
    - Student works, 1979 (Box-folder 15:21)
  - Miami University, Oxford, OH, Teaching papers and student works, 1979 (Box-folder 15:22)
  - Columbia University and Barnard Architecture College
    - Undergraduate program, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 15:23)
    - Program agenda, 1982 (Box-folder 15:24)
    - Miscellaneous, 1982 (Box-folder 15:25)
    - GSAP and Junior Studio, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 15:26)
    - Precis, Journal of the Graduate School of Architecture and Planning, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 15:27)
    - General, 1987 (Box-folder 15:28)
  - Columbia University
    - Fall studio documents, 1980 (Box-folder 15:29)
    - Graduate studios, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 15:30)
    - Women's Exhibition, 1981-1982 (Box-folder 15:31)
    - Pat Morton Master Thesis, 1982 (Box-folder 15:32)
    - Thesis seminar, 1982 (Box-folder 15:33)
    - Graduate studios, Factory in Lawrence, MA, 1983 (Box-folder 16:1)
    - Notes and correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 16:2)
    - Photographs, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 16:3)
    - Alumni directory, 1984 (Box-folder 16:4)
    - Graduate Studio, 1987 (Box-folder 16:5-6)
    - Columbia University, GSAP, Third-year studio, Spring 1988 (Box-folder 16:7-9)
    - GSAP, Urban Design Studio, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:10)
    - GSAP, Urban Design Studio, Bryant Park Design Proposal, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:11)
    - GSAP, Urban Design Studio, Newspaper Clippings 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:12)
    - GSAP, Urban Design Studio, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:13)
    - Columbia University, Building Design Studio, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:14)
    - Building Design Studio, Slides, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16:15)
  - University of Pennsylvania, Miscellaneous, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 16:16)
  - Escuela Technica Superior De Architectura, Barcelona, Spain, Correspondence, 1982 (Box-folder 16:17)
  - University of North Carolina at Charlotte, 1984 (Box-folder 16:18)
  - University of Sydney, Lecture, 1990 (Box-folder 16:19)
  - New Jersey Institute of Technology, Dean Search, 1990 (Box-folder 16:20)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1991 (Box-folder 16:21-22)
  - University of Cincinnati, 1991 (Oversize 21)
  - University of Buenos Aires, 1991 (Box-folder 16:23)
  - Untitled Travel Sketches, Toby Levy, 1987-92 (Box-folder 16:24)
  - Studio for Newark, Childbirth, 1977 (Box-folder 16:25)
  - Child Birth Research, Newspaper clippings and notes, n.d. (Box-folder 16:26)
- Series IV: Office Files 1967-1994
  - Subseries A: Lectures, 1972-1994
    - 1972-1978 (Box-folder 17:1)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 17:2)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 17:3)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 17:4)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 17:5)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 17:6)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 17:7)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 17:8)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 17:9)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 17:10)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 17:11)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 17:12-13)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 17:14)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 17:15-16)
    - 1991 (Box-folder 17:17)
    - 1992 (Box-folder 17:18)
    - 1993 (Box-folder 17:19)
    - 1994 (Box-folder 17:20)
  - Subseries B: Conferences and Symposia, 1967-1990
    - 1967-1971 (Box-folder 17:21)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 17:22)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 17:23)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 17:24)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 17:25)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 17:26)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 17:27)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 17:28-29)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 17:30)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 17:31)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 17:32)
    - 1989-1990 (Box-folder 17:33)
  - Subseries C: Juries and Advisory Boards, 1977-1991
    - 1977 (Box-folder 18:1)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 18:2)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 18:3)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 18:4)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 18:5)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 18:6)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 18:7)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 18:8)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 18:9)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 18:10)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 18:11)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 18:12)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 18:13)
    - 1990-91 (Box-folder 18:15)
  - Subseries D: Exhibitions, 1972-1990
    - Traveling Arrangements and Planning: "Women in American Architecture" Exhibition 1973-79 (Box-folder 18:17)
    - "Women in American Architecture: A Contemporary Perspective," at Brooklyn Museum, NY 1977 (Box-folder 18:21)
    - Women in American Architecture" exhibition installation in other cities 1977-78 (Box-folder 18:22)
    - Exhibitions 1972 (Box-folder 18:16)
    - 1975 (Box-folder 18:18)
    - 1976 (Box-folder 18:19)
    - 1977 (Box-folder 18:20)
    - 1978 (Box-folder 18:23)
    - 1979 (Box-folder 18:24)
    - 1980 (Box-folder 19:1)
    - Collections, 1980-90 (Box-folder 19:2)
    - Exhibitions 1982 (Box-folder 19:3)
    - 1983 (Box-folder 19:4)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 19:5)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 19:6)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 19:7)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 19:8)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 19:9)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 19:10)
    - Projected exhibition of diorama, drawings and models, n.d. (Box-folder 19:11)
    - 20th Century Design and Traveling Exhibition for Latin America, n.d. (Box-folder 19:12)
  - Subseries E: Awards and Fellowships, 1979-1990
    - 1979-1980 (Box-folder 20:1)
    - 1981 (Box-folder 20:2)
    - 1982 (Box-folder 20:3)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 20:4)
    - Portfolio Illustrations, 1986 (Box-folder 20:5)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 20:6)
    - 1990 (Box-folder 20:7)